Namaste. Salaam.
ناماستي. سلام.
Shalom. Sat Sri Akal.
شالوم. سات سري أكال.
Greetings to all of you from Pakistan.
مرحباً بالجميع من باكستان.
It is often said that we fear that which we do not know.
يقال دائماً أننا نخاف مما لا نعرفه.
And Pakistan, in this particular vein, is very similar.
وباكستان، في هذا السياق خاصة، مشابهة جداً.
Because it has provoked, and does provoke,
لأنها أثارات ، وما تزال تثير
a visceral anxiety in the bellies of many a Western soul,
القلق في بطون الكثير من الأرواح الغربية،
especially when viewed through the monochromatic lens
خاصة عندما يُنظر لها عبر العدسات آحادية اللون
of turbulence and turmoil.
للإضطرابات والقلاقل.
But there are many other dimensions to Pakistan.
لكن هناك عدة أبعاد أخرى لباكستان.
And what follows is a stream of images,
وما سيعقب هو سلسلة من الصور،
a series of images captured by some of Pakistan's
سلسلة من الصور تم التقاطها بواسطة بعض أكثر مصوري
most dynamic and young photographers,
باكستان الشباب الحيويين،
that aims to give you an alternative glimpse,
الذين يهدفون لتقديم لمحة بديلة،
a look inside the hearts and minds
نظرة داخل قلوب وعقول
of some ordinary Pakistani citizens.
بعض المواطنين الباكستانيين العاديين.
Here are some of the stories they wanted us to share with you.
ها هي بعض هذه القصص التي أردت تقاسمها معكم.
My name is Abdul Khan. I come from Peshawar.
أمسي عبدول خان. أتيت من بيشاور.
I hope that you will be able to see
أتمنى أنه يمكنكم رؤية
not just my Taliban-like beard,
ليس فقط لحية على غرار طالبان،
but also the richness and color
لكن أيضاً ثراء ولون
of my perceptions, aspirations and dreams,
تصوراتي، طموحاتي وأحلامي،
as rich and colorful as the satchels that I sell.
الملونة والغنية مثل الحقائب التي أبيعها.
My name is Meher and this is my friend Irim.
أمسي مهار وهذة صديقتي آيريم.
I hope to become a vet when I grow up
أتمنى أن أصبح مدربة حيوانات حينما أكبر
so that I can take care of stray cats and dogs
بحيث أستطيع العناية بالقطط والكلاب الضالة
who wander around the streets of the village
التي تحوم في طرق القرية
that I live near Gilgit, northern Pakistan.
لأنني أعيش في جليجيت، شمال باكستان.
My name is Kailash. And I like to enrich lives
أسمي كايلاش. وأنا أحب إثراء الحياة
through technicolored glass.
عبر تقنيات تلوين الزجاج .
Madame, would you like some of those orange bangles
سيدتي، هل ترغبين في بعض أساور البرتقال
with the pink polka dots?
مع تنقيطها باللون الوردي؟
My name is Zamin.
أسمي زامين.
And I'm an IDP, an internally displaced person,
أنا نازح داخلياً،
from Swat.
من إقليم سوات.
Do you see me on the other side of this fence?
هل تروني من الجهة الأخرى لهذا السور؟
Do I matter, or really exist for you?
هل أنا مهم، أو أنني موجود بالنسبة لكم؟
My name is Iman. I am a fashion model,
أسمي إيمان. أنا عارضة أزياء،
an up-and-coming model from Lahore.
ونجمة صاعدة في الموضة من لاهور.
Do you see me simply smothered in cloth?
هل تروني ببساطة مخنوقة في الملابس؟
Or can you move beyond my veil
أو يمكنكم الخروج على إرادتي
and see me for who I truly am inside?
ورؤية حقيقتي من الداخل؟
My name is Ahmed. I am an Afghan refugee
أسمي أحمد. وأنا من اللاجئين الأفغان
from the Khyber agency.
من منطقة خيبر.
I have come from a place of intense darkness.
لقد جئت من مكان شديد الظلام.
And that is why I want to illuminate the world.
ولهذا السبب أرغب في إضاءة العالم.
My name is Papusay.
أسمي بابوساي.
My heart and drum beat as one.
دقات قلبي ودقة الطبل شئ واحد.
If religion is the opium of the masses,
إذا كان الدين أفيون الشعوب،
then for me, music is my one and only ganja.
إذاً بالنسبة لي، الموسيقى هي شفائي ومدينتي.
A rising tide lifts all boats.
المد الصاعد يرفع كل القوارب.
And the rising tide of India's
والمد الصاعد في الهند
spectacular economic growth
هو النمو الإقتصادي المذهل
has lifted over 400 million
الذي رفع أكثر من 400 مليون
Indians into a buoyant middle class.
هندي الى الطبقة الوسطى المزدهرة.
But there are still over 650 million Indians,
لكن ما يزال أكثر من 650 مليون هندي،
Pakistanis, Sri Lankans, Bangladeshis, Nepalese,
باكستاني، سيرلانكي، بنغالي، نيبالي،
who remain washed up on the shores of poverty.
الذين ما تزال تجرفهم الأمواج الى شواطئ الفقر.
Therefore as India and Pakistan, as you and I,
إذاً كما أن الهند وباكستان، مثلك ومثلي،
it behooves us to transcend our differences,
فإنه حري بنا تجاوز الخلافات
to celebrate our diversity,
للإحتفاء بالتنوع.
to leverage our common humanity.
للإستفادة من إنسانيتنا المشتركة.
Our collective vision at Naya Jeevan,
رؤيتنا الجماعية في نايا جيفان،
which for many of you, as you all recognize,
التي بالنسبة لكثيرون منكم، كما علمتم جميعاً،
means "new life" in Urdu and Hindi,
تعني "الحياة الجديدة" في لغتي الاردو والهندية،
is to rejuvenate the lives of millions of low income families
ولتجديد حياة ملايين من الأسر ذات الدخول المنخفضة
by providing them with affordable access
بتزويدهم بفرصة سهلة للوصول
to catastrophic health care.
للخدمات الطبية الباهظة الثمن.
Indeed it is the emerging world's first
بالطبع أن نرفع العالم الناشئ أولاً
HMO for the urban working poor.
لدرجة العمل في المناطق الحضرية الفقيرة.
Why should we do this as Indians and Pakistanis?
لماذا يجب أن نفعل هذا كهنود وباكستانيين؟
We are but two threads cut from the same cloth.
نحن قطعتين من نفس القماش.
And if our fates are intertwined,
ومصيرنا متشابكة
then we believe that it is good karma, it is good fortune.
وبعد ذلك نعتقد أن هذه كرامة جيدة، أنها ثروة جيدة.
And for many of us, our fortunes do indeed lie
وبالنسبة لكثيرين منا، فأن ثرواتنا بالطبع تقع
at the bottom of the pyramid. Thank you.
في قاعدة الهرم. شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Chris Anderson: Fantastic. Just stay up here.
كريس أندرسون: رائع. أنتظر لحظة هنا.
That was fantastic.
كان هذا رائعاً.
I found that really moving.
لقد وجدت أنه مؤثر حقاً.
You know, we fought hard to get at least
تعرف، لقد حاربنا بضراوة لنحصل على الأقل
a small Pakistani contingent to come.
على حضور باكستاني ليحضروا.
It felt like it was really important.
لقد شعرنا بأنه من الضروري جداً
They went through a lot to get here.
لقد مروا بالكثير من الصعاب للوصول الى هنا.
Would the Pakistanis please just stand up please?
أرجو أن يقف الباكستانيين هنا
I just really wanted to acknowledge you.
لقد أردت فعلاً أن أقوم بشكركم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you so much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم.